The goal is to get these movie poster images somehow.
本节课的目标是以某种方法收集这些电影的海报图片
The one displayed here is for E.T.
此处显示的便是《ET 外星人》的海报
So, Rotten Tomatoes actually does have an API and it does provide audience scores,
所以 烂番茄网的确有一个 API 且提供观众评分
which means we could have hit the API instead of scraping it
这表示我们本能够通过 API
off of the Rotten Tomatoes web page earlier in the lesson.
而非从本课早先提到的 Rotten Tomatoes 网页上采集数据
But this API doesn't provide posters and images, unfortunately.
但很不幸的是 这个 API 不提供海报和图片
Even if they did, this API is one that requires you to
即使提供
apply for access before using it via a proposal form.
此 API 要求在使用前 首先得通过申请表申请访问
This isn't uncommon.
这种做法很常见
This API wasn't going to be scalable enough for use in this course anyway.
这个 API 的扩展性无法满足本课程中的使用
When given a choice the rule of thumb is always pick the API over scraping.
如果可以选择 按照经验我们一定会选用 API 而非数据采集
As this answer on Stack Overflow suggests,
正如 Stack Overflow 网页上的答案所建议
pause the video and take a second to read this if you'd like.
如果感兴趣 你可以暂停视频 花一点时间读读这个建议
Scraping is brittle and breaks with
采集操作易出错而且与重设网页布局分裂
web layout redesigns because the underlying HTML has changed.
因为潜在的 HTML 发生了改变
Imagine for a second that we did have access to the Rotten Tomatoes API though.
假如我们已访问到 Rotten Tomatoes 网站的 API
APIs on the left and their access libraries,
左边是 API 及其访问库
an example of which is on the right allow
右侧为库的范例
programmers to access data in a super simple manner.
它允许程序员以超简单方式访问数据
You'll learn difference between an API and an access library in a second.
你很快就会明白 API 和 访问库之间的差异
But first here's an example of how simple it would
首先看一个例子
have been to get the audience score data using
看看使用 Rotten Tomatoes API 获取观众评分数据有多容易
the Rotten Tomatoes API and this rotten tomatoes API access library called rtsimple.
这个 API 访问库称为 rtsimple
As written here rtsimple is a wrapper written in Python for the Rotten Tomatoes API.
正如此处所写 rtsimple 是用 Python 为 Rotten Tomatoes API 编写的装饰器
First, we import the rtsimple library as the alias rt then we set our API key.
首先 我们导入 rtsimple 库为别名 rt 然后设置 API 密钥
This is what Rotten Tomatoes is hiding behind that proposal form vetting process.
这就是 Rotten Tomatoes 隐藏在申请表审批程序后的内容
And we create this movie object with
我们用一句简单代码和 电影 ID 创建这个电影对象
this simple bit of code and the movie ID, which for E.T.
对 《ET 外星人》 而言
is 10489, and then we access the
ID 是 10489
ratings using.ratings and the audience_score in these brackets.
然后我们用 .ratings 和 括号中的 audience_score 访问观众评分
If we had an API key and were to run this cell,
如果我们有一个 API 秘钥 并运行此单元格
the audience_score rating of 72 for E.T would have been printed out below here.
《ET 外星人》 的观众评分 72 分将于下方打印出来
So compared to scraping this is less brittle and I'd argue despite
与采集数据相比 这个操作不易出错
beautifulsoup being pretty simple I'd argue that this is more intuitive code.
尽管用 Beautiful Soup 操作相当简单 但我认为这是一个更直观的代码
So because we can't use the Rotten Tomatoes API for this lesson,
由于我们在本节课中不能使用烂番茄的 API
enter Wikipedia, and specifically, MediaWiki.
请进入维基百科 具体说是 MediaWiki
MediaWiki is an API that hosts all of the Wikipedia data.
MediaWiki 是存储维基百科所有数据的 API
Next, you'll get into how APIs work under the hood using
接下来 你会熟悉 API 在使用 MediaWiki 的包装下如何运作
MediaWiki and a popular access library for Python.
以及在 Python 常见访问库下如何运作